PRASANG SHARMA

Mobile App Developer & UI/UX Designer

Email: prasang.sharma7@gmail.com

Contact: (+91) 8681-070-970

Portfolio: prasang7.github.io

Github:

github.com/prasang7

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/prasang7

PROIECTS

DERT — Doctor's Emergency Rescue Task App

Built a cross-platform emergency notification SOS mobile app for Doctors of Indian Medical Association – to solve a major social issue of 'violence-against-doctors'. The app is live and is being currently used by 350+ doctors in Dehradun for past 1 year and 3 months. Looking forward to implement it in other cities of India. (Project Description: https://prasang7.github.io/projects/dert.html)

Travis — Traffic Solution Mobile App

Travis is a traffic and road safety assistance mobile app, that assists pedestrians, drivers & passengers in real-time. I created this app for Ford's International Hackathon and with this project, I was able to win the Hackathon. The project won a total of \$19,500 USD of prize money along with an international recognition. (Project Description: https://prasang7.github.io/projects/travis.html)

Cambuzz — Open Source Youth Networking Platform

Lead App Developer, Team of 9 students (Webapp & Android). Cambuzz is a centralized information system (dedicated mobile app and website), with track teacher feature and in campus Q/A forum. Successfully used by 2300+ students of VIT University. I also worked on designing UI/UX of the app along with it's core programming. (Project Description: https://prasang7.github.io/projects/cambuzz.html)

EXPERIENCE

SafeRide Inc, CA, USA — Mobile App Developer and Designer

JUNE 2017 - SEP 2017

Worked as a mobile app developer on the react-native platform to develop cross platform mobile apps in the initial phase of the internship. In the later phase I worked as a UI/UX designer and designed multiple UX process (core-app designs, website logins, user manuals). It was a work-from-home internship of 4 months.

VOLOC, Chennai — Mobile App Development Team Lead

APRIL 2016 - SEP 2016

Lead a team of 8 Android Developers, to collaboratively build VOLOC's Android app with core java based app development. Working parallel to the web-dev team, I Created base activities/pages of app along with designing it's UI/UX. Worked on integrating the base functionalities of the app. Worked on testing and efficiency checks of the app as well.

EngineerBabu, Indore — Software Engineering Intern

DEC 2015 - JAN 2016

Worked on MotorBabu App – vehicle repair & service booking app. Created the currently used login/signup system, and many internal pages/activities of the app. Worked predominantly on hooking the app with the API endpoints to fetch/send/update data on the server. Also worked on UI/UX of the app along with learning basic design tools.

EDUCATION

VIT University, Chennai

B. Tech - Computer Science & Engg. CGPA: 8.40/10.00

SICA School, Indore

Higher Secondary Score: 91.2%

AWARDS

World Finalist, (Top 10 Students in the world)

World UX Championship'16

October 2016 - Austria, Europe. Prize: All-expenses-paid trip to Austria, Europe for a week.

Winner,

International Hackathon by Ford and Devpost.

Hackathon Winner, Best Student Application & Best Local Resident Award (Prize money: \$19,500 USD)

SKILLS

React-Native (Cross-platform Mobile App Dev) Android Application Development Javascript & ES6

Java

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and Experience Design

Sketch (Prototyping)

DESIGN TOOLS

Zeplin (Dev & Design Collaboration)